

# **Mohammed Abdel-latief**

UI/UX designer

Cairo, Egypt

### **About me**

I was born on **15 September 1984**, I'm from Egypt, Marsa Matrouh (google it, beautiful city). **Married** and have **one kid** (Bilal, 2 years baby boy).

I love to take an idea through **design** iterations and then perfectly code it up for users to enjoy. I'm as excited by the pixel perfect designs as I'm by the smart **HTML** markup, clever **CSS** and the perfect ease for **Javascript** web animation.

## **Experience**

#### Senior UI/UX Designer

Orange . Aug 2016 - Present

Working on the UX design and UI development of a large scale projects in both Egypt and France.

#### **UX Lead**

Nahdet Misr . Jun 2015 - Jul 2016 (1 yr 2 mos)

Coordinating a team of 4 designers, handleing all UI/UX related tasks in order to create a digital experience to the Educational book "Aladwaa" (www.Aladwaa.com), including creating a website and mobile app for the book.

#### **Senior UX Designer**

Sarmady (a Vodafone company) . Aug 2012 – Jun 2015 (2 yrs 11 mos)

Building a strong user experience and a unique user-centered design for a large scale web/mobile based projects.

#### **Graphic Designer & UI developer**

Taya IT . May 2009 - Aug 2012 (4 yrs 3 mos)

Started as a UI developer working only on the coding side, after two years the management decided to make use of my graphics skills, and I became a part of the design team ever since.

#### Web & Graphic Designer

Innoworx . Nov 2008 - May 2009 (7 mos)

Working on the user interfaces from both design and coding Perspective for web based projects. 002 0100 405 4845

**G** mabdellatief@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/mabdellatief

github.com/MohammedAbdellatief

dribbble.com/Domany

Bē behance.net/domany

codepen.io/Domany

www.domany.design

## Languages

**Arabic:** Native language

**English:** Professional proficiency

#### **Tools**

Sketch

Flinto

Framer studio

Invision

Mocups

Zeplin

Optimizly

Google ananlytics

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe illustrator

Adobe Aftereffects

#### **Education**

#### Faculty of arts, Tanta university

68% . 2005

License of arts, studied libraries and documentation science.

### Graphic design diploma, Premiere - digital art school

A . 2008

Diploma in visual and graphic design.

### Web design diploma, Premiere - digital art school

A- . 2008

Diploma in desiging for the web.

#### Design sprint Nanodegree program, Udacity

2018

Certificate at: confirm.udacity.com/YPDDEKZ5

### **Technical Skills**

#### **UX Research**

Stakeholder interview, User interviews, Field studies, Surveys, Personas Building, User Scenarios, User Stories, User FLows, Competitive analysis.

#### **Information Architecture**

Content startegy, Card sorting, Site maps, Journey maps, pages/content inventory, short-hand Flows, wire-flows.

#### **Prototyping**

Sketches and paper wireframes, Low/hi fidelity prototypes, Interactive prototypes.

#### **UX** Evaluation

Usability tests, A/B tests, Heuristic Analysis, Accessibility evaluation, Post-project Analytics.

#### Visual Design

Digital illustration, User interface design, Icons design, Styleguides.

#### **User Interface**

HTML5, CSS3, Sass, responsive UI, Vanilla Javascript, jQuery, web animation using GSAP & CSS3.

#### **Soft Skills**

Effective communication

Organized and Meticulous

Quick and continuous learner

Open to critique

Updated and open to new Trends

Sharp eye for details

Eye for Pixle perfect design

#### **Passions**

User interface design

Digital Illustration

Scalable vector graphics (SVG)

Interaction design

Web animation

HTML&CSS&JS prototyping

Sketching

### **Interests**



Drawing and sketching



Time with family



Travelling



Swimming